Hello, I'm your host David Bernard and
my guest today is Daphne Tidman,
speaker, writer, and freelance growth
adviser specializing in subscription
apps and other DTOC products. On the
podcast, I talk with Daphne about why
skipping user interviews is costing you
growth, how to bring your products aha
moment forward into your marketing, and
why your assumptions about why people
use your app might be wrong. Hey
Deafany, thanks so much for joining me
on the podcast today. Thanks for having
me. Really looking forward to chatting.
This topic is one that we've kind of
touched on on the podcast before, but we
haven't done a deep dive. I think that's
a shame. So I'm excited to have you on
and talk about jobs to be done. You've
done a webinar, some blog posts on the
Revenue Cat blog. So let's again what is
jobs to be done? So, it's definitely a
great topic to talk about because it's
something that once you understand it,
it changes everything the way you see
it. And it's getting away from like what
is it that your app actually does and
thinking instead like a job to be done
is like what is your end user trying to
achieve? What is the end goal? And I
always think of it as like they're going
from A to B and you're helping them
along the way in that journey and it's
working out what does that journey look
like and how can you support them to get
there rather than just thinking about
like look this is what we do these are
the features we have because so many
apps are constantly talking about we
have this feature that feature but
that's not why people use your app. How
do you discover those jobs to be done?
How do you go through and figure out how
people relate to your app in that way?
So, I think the most important part of
it in working it out is really speaking
to your end users and having those
interviews and trying to understand
like, okay, what led you to actually
using our app and treating it again as
like almost a journey that you came
along halfway in that journey. They
probably didn't just suddenly start
struggling in that very moment. They've
probably been trying to work it out for
a while and trying to figure out like
what was then the reason the problem
they were trying to solve and diving
really deep into that as to what were
they doing before that how were they
solving in the past and what then led
them in that moment to think hey let me
try out your app and that will really
tell you like okay what are they trying
to solve what are they trying to achieve
and asking really about like that
outcome what difference were they hoping
to see by using your app that's for me
the most valuable way of doing it But
often like when I'm trying to work this
out with a brand like I like to have
multiple data points. So the other thing
I also like to do is go through all the
reviews obviously there'll always be
some reviews that are just purely about
like the functionality of the app. Hey
crashed, I'm unhappy about this or great
app and that tells you nothing. But I've
also found that review mining and going
through like all the reviews and reading
the more in-depth reviews of like them
saying like oh I came across this
because I was really struggling with my
ADHD and I was trying to find a way to
better focus and someone recommended
this to me will also help you work out
like okay what are they trying to
achieve. The other thing I also like to
do is look at like okay with a survey
data working out who are the ones who
are staying the longest. So, who's been
subscribed for a while? Who's actively
using your app? They're not just
basically have a subscription they've
forgotten about, but they're actively
using your app. They're making the most
of it and asking them through a survey.
That's really a good technique if you
have a big database to make sure that
your interviews are more focused. But if
I could choose one thing, I always say
to interviews because that's everyone's
least favorite thing because it costs
the most time, but it's the most
valuable. Yeah, totally. When going
through that discovery process, how do
you think about kind of primary jobs to
be done and secondary jobs to be done
and how those relate to each other?
Example I've given on the podcast before
and what I think about constantly is you
know I still have my side project
weather app and it's interesting to me
that you know there is a primary job to
be done of like is it going to rain
tomorrow? You know what's the weather
like today? And I can kind of go through
and figure out some of those jobs to be
done. But then there's also like weird
subtle jobs to be done where kind of
weather is almost entertainment for
folks. Weather is a topic of discussion.
And part of the job to be done for some
people using my weather app or any
weather app is knowing the weather so
that you can have a conversation about
it later. So, oh, you know, it's going
to rain tomorrow or or gosh, wow, like
it's going to get really cold next week
or it's probably not something I would
use for messaging, you know, like this
is the best app to be able to talk about
the weather, but it is kind of like part
of the the subtlety of how people think
about using a weather app even if it's
not a primary. So how do you think about
those aspects of this primary jobs to be
done and the secondary jobs to be done
and even the you know apps where it's
maybe not as
taskoriented but maybe the job to be
done is a little more subtle. So I think
it's really good to get that layer
deeper of like what is it that's
actually driving them to come back
because that's also for the retention
side hugely important and also in terms
of your differentiator because a lot of
apps can tell the weather so you just
feel like messaging around like hey you
know you can find out what the weather
is tomorrow and you're not going to
stand out and I think it's actually in
those secondary more subtle things that
you allow things to stand out. So when
we did the painkiller versus vitamins
webinar with weltery, it's a health
tracking app. People love the data side
of it, but it's actually making it more
fun, making it almost like fun to check
out and like little learning moments and
almost as engaging as scrolling through
like, you know, X and reading these
little nuggets of wisdom that get people
back. So I think it's really good to
know those secondary ones. And even if
you don't use it in your messaging, they
might be what drives that retention
because they might be that extra side of
it that creates an emotional connection.
And I think when we talk about jobs to
be done, there's like the functional
drivers like purely like I'm trying to
solve this problem like I'm trying to
stay fit, but there's also the emotional
drivers like I'm, you know, I'm not
feeling as strong as I was. I feel like
I'm getting insecure about how I look.
And those emotional drivers, I'm not
saying like misuse them in any way, but
like I think they're stronger. They are
so much stronger than the functional
drivers. So I think even if they are
secondary, they might be stronger for
you to get it back. So I don't think you
always have to pick one or the other. I
think it's good to understand both sides
of it and to then work out like what do
you want to like show also. And that was
also a really good thing that came out
of the webinar when we were talking
about it was this example of rather than
trying to tell people with your
messaging. Like messaging is so much
more than that. It's not just the
language. It's how you're positioning
yourself. It's how you're bringing
things across by showing them things
rather than telling them. And like going
back to that world tree example, they
would basically pull in your data in the
onboarding and you'd immediately get
some insights about yourself in the
onboarding rather than tell you we can
give you insights. You mentioned another
category too. It is nice for folks when
they're thinking through this jobs to be
done discovery like what are these jobs
to be done? You also mentioned social
drivers. So you have functional drivers,
emotional drivers and social drivers. So
what is that social driver piece and how
should people be thinking about that?
Yeah. So I think with the social
assignments like we can pretend that
we're very rational people. We're really
not. Society's expectations and what
others expect of us plays a role in our
decision-m and also that desire for
connection. And we see that also growing
as a form of gamification in a lot of
apps of like how do we connect with
others that we might not even know that
we might have never met. And that that
can also create a driver to do things.
Like going back to like the workout,
it's the thing that we know we should do
but for a lot of us it is a struggle. It
is a struggle to do it. And so having
people hold you accountable and also
appreciate it when you do things like I
don't very actively use Traver, but I
always get like kudos from like a few
people who like always standardly are
like kind of supporting on there and I I
go on there to support them too,
especially when I know they're training
for a race or something or a competition
like and that social aspect can also be
a driver and a reason why you use
something. So that's also a
consideration, especially with apps
where there's a community scent or
there's some fun little gamification
about the social aspect. That can be a
big reason why they use your app is to
feel that connection. Yeah. The uh
founder of Ladder Fitness app, I had him
on the podcast twice now, but the most
recent episode, he talked about how
there's a new feature they added. It's
like a cheer feature where live while
you're working out, other people can
kind of cheer you on. And he said that
they they ran the data on that and
people getting cheered on was highly
correlated with additional retent or
like some amount of increase in
retention. I forget exactly the numbers
he shared, but it's exactly what you're
saying is that, you know, the latter app
is now more retentive for incorporating
those social dynamics into it. And then,
yeah, we see this a ton in community
apps. There's another health and fitness
app I've had on the podcast, uh, food
logging app, and they have a huge
community, and the community is a huge
driver of that long-term retention. So
yeah, there's so many examples of how
this social dynamic and again it's you
don't think of it as a job to be done.
You wouldn't necessarily say like the
job to be done with ladder is to get
cheered on in a workout. No, I mean how
would you reframe that then under this
kind of social driver? How would you
frame that as a as a social job to be
done? That's a good one. when I
experience this, I want this so that I
can is usually the framework I use in
framing these jobs to be done. And so I
would almost say like let's take ladder
as an example and I really can relate to
this because I've had it I use Pelaton
and I've had it also on Pelaton where
like someone random person claps me on
and I just suddenly start biking faster
and it's ridiculous because they can't
see me. They can maybe see how many like
output I've done but like I just like
start biking faster. So, I believe this
really does work. But I would say it's
like, okay, when I want to, let's say,
when I want to get stronger, I want to
feel supported and motivated to work out
so that I can stay consistent and see
the results. It's not the perfect
framing, but we're going on the spot
here. And I think like it's almost like
the how how you get your users there is
that social kind of driver. It's like if
you understand what drives them, you can
play on that to help them achieve their
job to be done. If you understand that
the social aspect of it matters to them
or helps keep them consistent and that
accountability, then you can play on
that. So it might not even be in your
job to be done sentence, but it might
almost be like that understanding that
that's what's driving them and knowing
their underlying drivers of that job to
be done might be what helps you then
help them to achieve their goal. If that
makes sense. So there's so many ways
once you start to understand the jobs to
be done for your app to then apply them
across all different parts of the app.
So let's start with messaging and how to
apply this understanding of jobs to be
done to messaging. And I've really liked
what you already said about like my
weather app is that if all I'm messaging
to people is you can check the weather,
there's a million apps that can check
the weather. And that's part of like
understanding these jobs to be done is
also helping identify those
differentiating features. So how do you
work that into messaging and then how
impactful can that be in more effective
messaging? Yeah. So I think my first
step is always narrowing it down because
I think that's something that a lot of
apps struggle with is that there's quite
a few potential ones and then when they
try to cover all of it it's really hard
to get that in there because you you
know you are more limited in like okay
how many places and how much can I
communicate and obviously in the end of
the day you can always personalize it
all or make different personalized flow
but you kind of want to have this
starting point of like what is my
initial messaging so I always first with
the jobs to be done try narrow it down a
bit. You should have already narrowed it
down by only speaking to those like high
spending users and those high potential
ones. But then I also look at like what
is the problem that we're trying to
solve? How good are we at actually
solving that problem? How good a
solution are we for that? And how much
chance is there that we can
differentiate? And that's where like
another part of my research which we
haven't talked about yet is comes in
which is competitor analysis and
understanding which angles the
competitors are going on. Because back
to the weather app, like if everyone's
just saying, you know, check it within a
moment or talk about the weather, like
then you're not going to stand out on
that. And then I'll narrow that down.
And then what I'll do before I integrate
it into all the messaging of the app
itself is I'll test it first. And if
you're running ads, meta ads are great
for this because what I've done in the
past is I've literally tested very
similar like visuals with different
messaging overlay on them and different
messaging in the text and then tested
those against each other first on like
the job to be done level with a more
general like image that isn't skewing
people too much in one direction or
another and then narrowing it down of
like do we want to talk about pains? Do
we want to talk about the gains uh of
what people are trying to, you know, get
in terms of benefits? Do we want to talk
very literally about the jobs to be
done? Do we want to talk about the
situations when you're experiencing
this? This could help you. There's
different ways of bringing across. So, I
tend to narrow that first down within
the ads. And everyone's always like,
"Meta is so visual. It's so visual, but
it's insane like the differences I've
seen in like the clickthrough rates just
with like these different jobs to be
done." And then I start to see like,
okay, how can I then start to not only
be able to like like what we talked
about before, like bring it across in a
copy way, but how can I bring it across
in a visual way? And so when we're
talking about messaging and integrating
it, we need to be looking at every
single visual we do, every single
message we do, like how can we bring
this across to the user in a way that it
then resonates with them. And if you've
done also that review mining and gone
through all those reviews and kept like
a nice log of the reviews and yes, you
can speed it all up with AI, but I
really believe strongly in also just
spending a few hours just completely
immersing yourself in the language.
You'll have this extra benefit on top of
that with the messaging for the copy
side of it where suddenly your language
becomes more human. It starts to
resonate more. And so like I would start
really first with like the acquisition
side, not to like improve acquisition,
but to use it as a way to test different
messaging. And once you've tested that
in a few different ways, you can also
use emails for this. If you've got a
good size email base, you can test with
push notifications. You can test this in
different ways. Once I start to get
confident of like, hey, we're
consistently seeing this win. That's
when I start to test integrating it step
by step and seeing like how can we bring
this better across. And you're actually
looking at in meta the different
conversion rates and even the different
monetization of the user depending on
the way you frame the job to be done.
Yeah. So I'm literally looking at like
okay if they have enough data and the
cost per trial for example is low enough
then we can do it based on that. That's
the ideal. If it's not or if they're a
very new app and they don't have big
budgets then I'll look on clickthrough
rates and see like what seems to be
resonating better versus the rest. I
will say when I do it on a clickthrough
rate basis because clickthrough rate
doesn't always perfectly correlate I
will try to run a few tests and see if I
can test it somewhere else. I've also
right away like used uh for example a
usability hub to run 5-second tests with
two messaging and ask people like what
their preference is and why and like
what stood out. That's also really
really good in refining it because
sometimes you use a word that just
triggers people the wrong way or people
don't understand what you mean. you're
trying to be too smart. And so that can
also like if you feel like hey I really
don't seem to be getting it right or I
feel like there's something quite off
but I don't know what of getting a bit
more qualitative feedback on it. How do
you think about different personas too
in latter you know my wife is a persona
which is so different than like me as a
persona and you know there's so many
different people and those people do
have different perceptions of those jobs
to be done. So yeah, how do you hone in
on that? Because even in the AB testing,
maybe overall one message resonated
more, but the other message did resonate
well with a different audience. How do
you think about the personas in that?
The reality is we rarely have just one
job to be done and we rarely just have
like one way of like resonating with
that job to be done. So I first try to
get the most out of that job to be done
because I think like people are very
quick to try and do everything at the
same time and I will build a persona
around that job to be done. I don't So
for me personas aren't about fluffy
demographics. They're really about like
what is the person trying to achieve?
What are their struggles? What are their
questions? And so I'll first really try
to get the most out of that job to be
done. But then I'll go back and see like
okay also again based on that survey
data we probably had a few jobs to be
done that were spending quite a bit that
were retaining that seem to love the app
and using it actively. So I'll go back
and like interview a different group and
try to work out okay what's different
with them versus the other one and how
can we basically then adjust the way
we're doing things to them. And I think
that's the great thing like about like
if you are using ads, Meta will find
people who will resonate with your ads.
So you can have different groups of ads,
one that's speaking to one job to be
done, one that's speaking to another.
Where I think it gets a bit tricky is
like obviously you can use like custom
like landers for them like in terms of
like what they're seeing in the app
store or if you're doing web to app, you
know, you can also do it there. But
where I think it gets a bit more tricky
is like once they're in the app, I think
that's where the personalization within
an onboarding flow is really important.
that you're adjusting like the content
that they're seeing and the experience
they're having in that onboarding to the
different jobs we've done. So like
Headspace for example, they're very
focused on sleep, but if you say you're
struggling with anxiety and stress,
you're going to see very different
content in app than if you click on
sleep. And I think that's how like apps
can also adjust is like making sure
they're asking the right questions and
onboarding to work out what like variant
of that job to be done are they speaking
to and what do they then need to show
them to to actually be able to onboard
them and resonate with them. Like
they're probably going to be showing a
different form of social proof. They're
probably going to be talking about
different content in the ad. They're
probably going to be using different
language. And I think that's where that
onboarding comes in. like it's not about
like learning it for your sake, but it's
learning it for their sake so that you
can still feel like it resonates with
you in terms of that job to be done. And
I think ladder does that too. I haven't
used it myself, but I've gone through
their like quiz once before and they
seem to ask you quite specific questions
where they're trying to work out who are
you and why are you potentially going to
use it. Yeah, totally. I finally started
using the ladder app myself recently.
It's funny because it gets to the point
is that I was using the app fitbod and
my job to be done was that I want to
specifically build some muscle. I'm 46
and all the, you know, experts are
saying to age well, you need to have a
decent amount of muscle mass on you. And
so I didn't associate ladder with that
as directly as I did Fitbot. And then
it's like in the home gym and I like to
customize my workout and like so like
there were all these like subtle things
where I just thought, "Oh, the ladder
app's not for me." But once I went
through the onboarding and then I found
the right. So what they do is they ask
you all these different questions and
then they pair you with a specific
coach. What's fascinating there is that
in the ladder app in a way they have
lots of different jobs to be done
because for my wife she has totally
different goals and what's great is they
have different coaches inside the app
that have different they almost kind of
satisfy those different jobs to be done.
And so I got paired with a coach who was
very spec like very specific to like
what I want in a workout. And then once
I finally did the workout, it was
incredible. They do kind of like take
you through this whole process of
figuring out who you are, what you want
out of a workout app, and then they pair
you with like the exact right person. We
talked about the app a ton on the
podcast. So, I almost feel embarrassed
saying I just started using it and then
also that we talk about it so much, but
they're just they're crushing it. I
mean, they're growing like crazy. And
part of the reason is things like this.
It's like the Fitbot app. It's great.
It's a great app. I used it for years.
I've really enjoyed it. But why I think
Ladder is doing so well is that they're
able to satisfy the jobs to be done of a
Fitbot app and a Pelaton app and another
it's like because they have so many
different coaches because they have such
great personalization. They're really
executing on this whole idea that we're
talking about with the jobs to be done
and it starts again all the way in their
advertising. I did want to kind of step
back to the advertising again before we
get into like using jobs to be done for
activation because I do want to dig
deeper into that too. Are there kind of
specific examples because I I love for
folks to be able to like tangibly take
away things and to try in their app in
their marketing and everything else. So,
what are specific examples of messaging
in screenshots, in marketing, in social
copy, in all the different ways you're
going to be getting attention and
funneling people into the app? You know,
how do you think about that messaging?
And what specific examples can you give
of of communicating those jobs to be
done in the messaging? And you mentioned
this concept I think in a blog post
message market fit like how do you fit
that message to that market. Yeah. So I
think there's two sides of it. So
there's the what's the messaging for
that market and then that messaging
breaks down into like the positioning
and the language that you use when it
comes to like the ad side of it. I think
one of the strongest formats that gets
used a lot is just the transformation.
And that's what, you know, I've been
hammered by Ladder of their ads, like
basically showing me like, "Hey, this is
what I look like before. Now I've been
using Ladder. This is what I look like
now." And Cooper, a personalized running
app, had a really good one of this
before where they were also showing like
the pain point of I actually knew the
person in the ad, Esme. She's a fitness
influencer, and she was showing like,
"Okay, this was my marathon time." And
then again and again, and each time I'm
not improving. I'm getting similar
times. And then I started training with
Cooper and I've actually, you know, I'm
training less, I'm feeling better, and
I've finally got my marathon time down
and I'm hitting the like, you know, the
goal I want. And so I think that
transformation is such a good one and
makes like a really good like uh because
then it's like what you said like it was
only when you saw people like you that
you thought it was for you. And I think
like that's like format of like seeing
people like you with the same struggle
trying to do the same thing works really
well. And one of the examples I've given
recently is of this app called Tractive
which is a dog tracking app. And they
are a combination of an app and a
physical product. A tracker that you can
build your dog. I have a half husky
which anyone who has a husky or knows
huskys well know that they are notorious
for running away. My dog likes to run
away and I saw a million of their ads,
but all their ads were 35% off on dog
and cat trackers, GPS and health
trackers. Like, if your ad is just
saying, "Get this disc this cow. This is
what we do." That's not speaking to
someone's job to be done. But then I
read one of their reviews and it was
about this Siberian husky that had run
off and the owner was so grateful she
had tractor. It gave us so much peace of
mind because the dog literally got in a
car with a stranger who was trying to
find their owner. They weren't stealing.
They were literally just driving around
and the owner could follow this car for
15 minutes to the vet that they decided
like, "Okay, let's just bring the dog
here until we can work out, you know,
with maybe the microchip roots front and
they could get their dog back and just
literally follow their dog on having
this little ride along with a random
stranger." And like I was like, if I saw
an ad showing this, I would have bought
this years ago, but it took me losing my
dog for the 10th time and multiple
people telling me, you're like, you're
an idiot trying to fix this with an Air
Tag. You keep losing your dog. Either
you don't let him loose or you put him
on um you know, or you get a better
tracker. For me to realize this was the
solution I needed. And so I could have
bought it 5 years ago. They could have
had so much more money from me if id
realized that I didn't just didn't know
that I needed a GPS tracker. I didn't
think that was the solution. I spent
ages trying to train my dog. I spent
ages like trying to find alternative
ways of doing it with long leashes, with
using an air tag, but I just didn't
process like that that GPS tracker would
work so much better until I actually
lost my dog again. And I just followed
him through the forest on his little
wander around until I could get him back
on be like, "Okay, you you've lost
walking loose duties." So I think like
trying to bring to life that journey
either the start of the journey or where
they can be is one of the most powerful
ad formats out there. And there's a
reason why ladder who you're right are
crushing it. And I've been tempted to
use apps so much from all the ads I've
seen just being very strict on myself
because I just got my Pelaton and my
Pelaton prescription. But it's because
it's like you say, it's exactly like
they're speaking so clearly to like my
pain boy of like, hey, you know, you
want to get like more into shape. You
want to do it efficiently and not
overtrain. You want to feel not just
like that you look a certain way, but
you feel strong. You feel good. And
they're showing literally people who
look exactly like me and the
transformation they're seeing that I'm
like, I'm so tempted by this, but I
really shouldn't.
Yeah. Yeah. There really is such a good
example. Another good example I've been
seeing lately and and I don't think they
would frame it this way, but in this
conversation, it dawned on me that so
many of the strategies I'm seeing on
TikTok end up being kind of jobs to be
done strategies. So, Calai is a great
example. Like, they've been blowing up
lately and they pay a lot of
influencers. There's a little bit of
mixed messaging on Twitter. people
people act as if it's fully organic, but
they actually pay a ton of creators to
create this. So, it's it's a different
form of paid marketing when you pay UGC
creators. And I think even they're
putting money behind some of that as
well. But when you look at some of their
ads, the ads are brilliant because it's
a Tik Tok like day in the life of or or
different things like I mean there's so
many different formats they've used. But
one of the ones I saw they just
incorporated Cali into their normal
routine. And so the job to be done is
like you know wanting to track your food
but tracking your food is a hassle. And
so they show them like going to a
workout and then they're coming home and
they're eating the meal and then they
just take a photo of the meal and it
tells you the calories and then they
move on with their day. It's almost like
it's not an ad because it's in passing
that they just happen to show it. But it
ends up being so compelling because we
all know if you're trying to lose
weight, you really should track your
food, but tracking your food is a
hassle. And they've and to your point,
what's the differentiation of Cal AI?
Take a picture. And so they're very
almost subtly working it into this Tik
Tok that can go viral and get more
attention because it it's not an ad, but
then they're showing the job to be done
in such a powerful way because instead
of it being this big hassle pulling out
the app and logging your food, you just
take a picture. I think that's a great
example of, you know, again, I don't
think they would they didn't sit down
and think through the jobs to be done
framework, but it works out that way.
And by sitting down and thinking through
the jobs to be done framework, you can
start creating those kind of ads that
really do more directly show off the
differentiation of the app and how it
satisfies those jobs to be done in a
better way. I think like an if you like
were like okay ignored the job to be
done framework a different way of almost
thinking about it where you're indeed
doing this accidental thing which it
sounds like they're doing is they've
realized what their aha moment is like.
what is the moment that people realize
this is something I need to achieve
whatever they're trying to achieve and
they're just working out like how can I
bring that forward in the journey and to
help bring it across it and the reason
it's working is because it's speaking to
that have to be done of like hey I want
to be able to track it with ease but
it's it's just bringing that almost
forward and that's what I was also
saying about like show don't tell rather
than having an ad saying like we do this
it's so easy it takes 2 seconds I think
what we need to remember is there's so
much emotions like even if it's not an
emotional driver leading them to use it.
There's always emotions around these
things. Like you can say like, "Oh, I
just want to learn Spanish because I'm
getting married in Spain next month and
it's helpful to speak Spanish." But
there's always that emotional drive of
this insecure moment and that feeling
stupid that you can't say something and
that fear of mispronouncing. And I think
like you might get people on board just
speaking to the functional, but I think
you hit a certain ceiling with that and
you get past that ceiling by
understanding the emotional drivers
behind a job to be done and really
speaking to that and finding different
ways to bring that across. And the thing
is is like, you know, you said they were
paying those people, but those people
were probably also just being like,
okay, how can I show this? Let me show
it as part of my life. And it's
actually, ironically, it's so easy to
almost find these different angles and
stuff when you do it that way because
you don't have to come up with it
yourself. You look at your customers,
you speak to your customers, and they'll
give you all these ideas. And like
whenever a brand also says like, "I'm
running out of ideas or like angles with
the ad side." Like, yes, there's
different ways you can ask AI to do it,
but I think the most powerful ones are
just watching and learning from your
customers and seeing how they're doing
it. Yeah, totally. You said something in
there that I thought was really
fascinating is bringing the aha moment
into the ads. And again, I want to get
to the activation and onboarding and
stuff, but that is in a way, you know,
starting the onboarding process and and
and getting that aha moment into the ad
is so powerful. And I had never thought
of it quite that way before. It's like
if you have an aha moment, can you work
that into the ad in some way that kind
of brings people into the app already
excited, already motivated, already kind
of understanding that aha moment cuz I
think in a way ladder failed you because
you only realized you needed them when
you went through the whole onboarding
and it was the same issue I had with
tractive like I only realized I really
needed them when I'd basically had the
same issue multiple times and exhausted
all other options. But if they'd
understood like what was the app you
were using before that and see that's
what's funny though was the app I was
using is FitPod. What's funny is I never
saw a ladder ad. I think that was my
problem is that I talked to the CEO. I
heard about the app, but for some reason
I never got ladder ads. And I don't use
Instagram a ton, but I use it enough
that I should have seen an ad. So for
whatever reason I didn't ever see an ad.
And so maybe that was the missing piece
was that their ads would have convinced
me, but I never saw one. And maybe that
was intentional. Maybe you weren't the
like primary jobs to be done that
they're focusing on because I do feel
like they're also really heavily going
after this kind of like a female
audience that and that might just be the
ads because of the ads I'm seeing. I'm
assuming this, but like a female
audience that's very focused on like
getting stronger without, you know,
getting overly buff and like being more
confident around it. But I think it's
like if they could understand like
there's a reason why you switched and I
think understanding also like what's
that feeling underneath like what would
lead you to switch are you actually
missing what's not fulfilling you with
your current solution and that's often
question like one of the key questions I
ask people it's like okay what were you
using before this and it doesn't have to
be an app you know because you can also
track calories manually yourself and
write them down you can also make your
own workout plans you can also go to
personal trainer or use a YouTube video.
So, it's like what were you using before
and like what's the reason why you're
not happy with it? What's leading you to
consider something else or like if you
weren't considering something else, what
was the reason that when you saw
something else that you were like, you
know what, let me try this instead. And
I think like yeah that's why that like
once you really understand that then you
can work out like okay what's there's
the aha moment that keeps you on board
but there might also be another aha
moment that helps you realize it's time
to switch because most of the time
people aren't you know they might not be
100% happy but they're not actively
looking and that's where I think that
like aha moment bringing that in earlier
and that's why I was like with lad it's
like if you had seen an ad it was almost
like I think they do quite heavily like
a web to app funnel if I'm not mistaken.
But if it wasn't a web to app funnel
like you almost want to think about like
okay with the ad with the app store
where are all these mo there's so many
moments before you get to the onboarding
already that you can start to you know
create that feeling that they understand
you and that get that almost I have like
this is actually what I need because
with the competition there is now like
it's never been easier to make an app. I
think you said that in one one of the
recent podcasts like it's so easy to
make an app these day like you can't
wait until they're in the app to get
them to that moment. I think that's also
what's really like changed in the last
like 5 to 10 years is like there's more
and more pressure for us to bring that
in earlier and fight to build that trust
and but when we do there's more spending
power than before because that's the
other thing that you saw in the state of
subscription apps is the amount people
are spending seems to also be going up
if I'm not mistaken. Yeah, since we
turned this into a ladder product market
fit seminar. Sorry. Yeah, I haven't even
used the app. That's the worst part.
It's so unintentional. I've only used it
once because it was just last week. But
in talking through that, it made me
realize that the reason I didn't use it
was because I've had lower back issues
since my early 20s. And what I liked
about FitBot was that I was in control
of the exercises. I built my own plans
and I built them around knowing which
exercises trigger my back and being
careful to not do things where I know,
you know, my form or whatever. So the
aha moment for me in ladder and I think
this is a recent addition and so this is
maybe why but the aha moment was that
they actually make it now so easy and
honestly even better than fit to
customize the workout to where you can
hit the right muscle group with like
different exercises and it's really easy
like the the user experience of
switching out the exercises to
accommodate your needs is really really
good and that was the aha moment was
when I was able to like go through the
workout and like in like seconds
customize it. So I don't you know it's
like I don't know if they could if
that's a strong enough job to be done
for enough people. I mean maybe I'll
send this episode to Greg the CEO and
tell him they should maybe do some
experiments with the job to be done of
people who you know have specific needs
and are worried that a workout app is
going to force them to do exercises that
hurt them or you know are problematic.
Whereas now the app is so good at being
able to just go through and and make
those customizations. And I think that
kind of touches on another key part of
like with like a job to be done like
logically we think everyone just wants
to achieve that and if we show them they
can achieve that that they'll do that.
But like you said like there's you had
the concern up front will this hurt my
back? You know will I be able to create
something that I need? And when you saw
that that was the case you were like
okay great let me try this out. That's
the other thing I always ask people.
It's like, okay, what almost stopped you
from signing up? What kind of concerns
did you have? And sometimes people don't
know it and then I ask them, have you
recommended this to friends and family?
And I'll say like, you know, yeah, I
recommended it to this person. I asked
them, what questions did they ask you?
Because they'll forget what they might
have been worried about because they
want to confirm like, hey, no, I made
the right choice. I wasn't concerned.
But they'll remember the things that
other people asked them, what came up
because then it's like uncomfortable.
it's like, "Oh, I encourage you to do
this." And you're basically like, "Will
it actually do this? Did I actually know
if it did that or not?" Because
sometimes you can't answer those
questions. And so, I think that's also a
key part of it is like again like it
gives you so much content when you
understand these jobs to be done because
you don't only just speak to like
showing the transformation, but you can
also then lower the funnel like speak to
like hey all these different concerns
like can't do certain exercises, no
stress. you can customize it completely
to what you need to prevent yourself
getting injured. Like there's so many
different ways you can then bring that
in and create also content around that.
But that's why I preach those interviews
so much because I'm like you only
realize this stuff by speaking and
having these conversations. That's such
a great one too of asking those
questions of what stopped you. you know,
if people don't end up in the app, I
guess this is the more like user
research kind of things where you're
doing user research with people who have
never used the app, didn't see an ad,
and then you just go through and you
walk them through the process and then
then ask those kind of questions or how
do you get at these blocking points? And
I guess you could do it in the app at
different stages of the funnel where
people drop off the funnel, figuring out
why they dropped off the funnel, but
yeah, how do you figure out those like
blockers? I'd probably combine it with
something else that you know we're
talking about these huge apps right now
and the reality is that most apps don't
have a huge database always to work with
especially if they're just starting out
and I work a lot with startups so I
really know and feel that pain so I
would say like if you want to like speak
to people who've never got that far and
like do those kind of like interviews
with them I would look at like what
other solutions fulfill your jobs to be
done and then recruit users for example
using a platform platform and I have no
affiliate with them but like for example
user interviews.com or respondent.io IO
like use a platform like that to recruit
users who have used similar solutions in
solving the job to be done and then
asking them a question about like okay
which of these is a painoint for you and
just give them a load of like bogus
options in there that they don't that
you're not asking them like hey have you
struggled with this painoint yes or no
because everyone will just say yes then
but like making it more difficult for
them to work out what's the right answer
and then you can basically indeed do
like those interviews with those people
who have never even converted, might not
even know you yet. And first, what I
tend to do is work out their job to be
done. Again, confirm, figure out like
what what solutions are they using, what
do they like and dislike, where have
they looked for alternatives, and then
do exactly what you said, like a user
test with them and walking through it
and then getting them to talk out loud
through their experience of it to see
like, okay, where are they getting the
hesitations? What questions are they
having? What's not clear? That tends to
be something I do slightly later in the
process because I want to first work out
like are we on the right track with this
and then once we've kind of like
validated this is the messaging this is
the angle we've improved our on boarding
around this have we actually done it
well enough have we actually got it
across where are the places that we're
still not working out because you can do
it before that for sure too but I think
it's so much more powerful to do it once
you've actually understood like what
you're trying to bring across and you've
refined that initially to really take
get then to the next level because again
I'm always thinking like people won't
want to do five rounds of this because
everyone's always you know doesn't don't
have enough time to do this but it is
very impactful. Yeah. But these are the
things that make or break. I mean just
talking through this is just a reminder
to me. I've done some user testing in
the past but I have not done it recently
and like I'm not talking to users in my
side project tab. Why? Because it's
hard. I have a full-time job. It's like
I squeeze in a few hours a week if that.
But these are the things that make or
break. This is how you grow and become a
much better stronger app. Is not just
your own individual product intuition,
but it's actually talking to users. It's
a fantastic reminder. And for those
folks listening and thinking like I
don't have time, this is too hard. It's
like, well, you know, if you're
struggling and you're spending hours and
hours and hours and hundreds of hours on
product development, you're spending
hundreds of hours on marketing, you're
spending hundreds of hours on other
things, like this is going to
supercharge all of those things going
out and talking to users. And yes, it's
hard, but you got to figure it out. It
will also save you time because you'll
end up doing less features. You'll
remove things that aren't helping people
on that journey. like you end up
refining your product road map so much
because of it versus trying to test
everything. You'll get really a lot
smarter in terms of testing. And the
challenge I'm going to give you for this
is cuz it's a web app, right? It's
helping people. So, you can literally go
out to a park and just put it in
people's hands and like offer to buy
them a coffee from a local cafe or go
into a cafe and do it there. I had an
app that's like a 24/7 that app. I love
working with dog brands because I have a
dog. So, another dog example, but it
basically you can just send in like a
short video, short audio note if you're
having an issue with your dog or cat or
whatever pet and they'll get back to you
within minutes and let you know like,
hey, do you actually need to go to a
vet? What should you do? So, if you if
your dog eats something in the park, you
don't have to rush immediately most of
the time. But if you don't know that,
you kind of like do it out of panic and
spend hundreds. And so for this app,
like I basically went into my dog park
and just asked a load of people there
who were walking their dogs. We walked
the dog together, strangers I'd never
met before, and just asked them to test
the app. And I said I'll give them a
year free of it in as a thank you, like
a year subscription for free, as a thank
you for it. And I just asked them to go
through it, sign up, and just send them
one random question they have on their
mind about their pet. And if they didn't
know, I'd give them one. And I just go
through that flow. And I found so many
issues and so many things where it just
wasn't resonating. bringing things
across. It was clunky. It wasn't
working. And it took me just like an
hour or two of walking around the park
with my dog to get like so many
insights. I just put my phone record on.
Like it was very like lowkey, nothing
fancy, you know? So that's the other
thing I would say like if you say you
don't have time for this, next time
you're in a cafe, just strike up a
conversation. It's scary for the first
two times, but I promise you people are
actually like half the time find it
really intriguing and just like kind of
go along with it. I've done it even for
like non apps like a pension brand too
where just talked to random people cafe
bought a load of people coffees and
learned so much from all these random
people about like how the site is
performing. I'm sure lots of folks will
be mortified by that idea. But maybe you
can hire somebody who is more outgoing
and have them uh video record the
conversation or something. But I did
want to move on to activation. So, we
spent a ton of time talking about, you
know, getting the messaging right for
ads, for screenshots, for that initial
messaging, but then how do you translate
that into the activation moment and how
do you iterate on that to really dial in
the activation using jobs to be done?
Yeah. So I think when it comes to the
activation side, it's hopefully if
you've already integrated this before,
you've already kind of built that trust
of like, hey, you're going to have this
at a moment. But it's like, okay, how do
you now bring this across and how do you
start to like build a habit around this?
And I think what's really key with this
is understanding like what could prevent
them from actually consistently using it
and how can you make it easier or funner
to actually do it because I think for a
lot of jobs we done like we don't we say
we want to do one thing and this is
something again we talked about in that
painkiller fitin webinar bit it's like
we say we want to you know practice
gratitude but do we actually take the
time to do it? We say we want to learn a
language but do we actually take the
time to do it? And so like working out
what those kind of like barriers of them
achieving it in the past like what's the
reasons they failed to achieve that job
to be done in the past can then help you
work out like what is it that I need to
integrate into that and that's where I
think gamification often does come in
and making it uh even more fun or making
it more engaging to basically achieve
that and have that sense of progress and
so I think your whole activation is
about giving them that feeling of
progress and getting there. So, like I
was doing some work with like a
gratitude app and like one of the ideas
we talked about is like well why don't
we do like a 3-day challenge potentially
in the onboarding already and then
actually have them already do that first
gratitude practice so that they feel
like I've already achieved something.
I've made progress already. And I think
like that's why like a lot of these like
language apps like will immediately try
to get you to do your first lesson and
just make it as small as possible. So, I
think bringing into that activation,
it's like what is the tiniest step you
can get them to do to make them feel
like they're making progress from A to
B. Even if it's a false sense of
progression with a workout, you might
not immediately be able to work out in
that moment, but is the feeling that you
have a plan in place that you have
clarity? You know, does that almost like
give you that tick off feeling? And I'm
not talking about like just streaks or
that because like I think they're they
can be quite flawed as a mechanism but
that's a different topic. But it's that
feeling that you've progressed that
you've done this tiny thing where even
if it's just planning it like what gives
people the feeling that they're moving
towards achieving that job to be done
even if it's a false sense of progress
but it's just giving them that feeling
of let's help you get there. Yeah. You
keep saying false sense of progress, but
but honestly, I mean, I think this is
one of those like subtle secondary jobs
to be done. Is it, you know, what's one
of the jobs to be done of a gym
membership? Part of the job to be done
is making you feel guilty that you're
not using it and paying $50, $60 a month
and not ever going is part of the job to
be done because that's highly
motivating. I'm spending money. I'm
wasting money by not going to the gym.
So, even like you were saying with a
fitness app or even the gratitude app, I
think that's really cool how in the
onboarding you could even ask the
questions and and this would be, you
know, real direct progress. What are you
grateful for today? It's almost like you
can page by page step them through what
is the gratitude practice and then at
the end like congrats, you've done it.
You've successfully completed day one.
Now move on to day two. and and but you
can work it in in a more subtle ways to
help them make progress. And then, you
know, like you said with the health and
fitness app, the plan is is progress.
Like having a plan in place, having
being ready to work out versus just
showing up and like having to figure it
out on the spot. I mean, again, that
bring this back to me and ladder, but
that was part of my problem with FitBod
was that they do have an automatic
feature that automatically generates a
workout, but I never liked the workout.
So then every time I would go work out,
I would go through and have to customize
and customizing the workout would take a
long time. So then I created some preset
workouts, but then I only had two preset
workouts and I'd alternate between them
and then I got bored of those two
workouts. And so having that plan in
place and that's what's now the killer
job to be done about ladder is that I
have a personal trainer super
experienced super talented pre-selecting
all the workouts for the week. All I
have to do is show up and then it only
takes me a couple of seconds to
customize it and then I'm on and going.
And so having that plan in place is part
of the job to be done of a fitness app,
of a meditation app, of a lot of these
apps. There probably are examples of
false progress as well, but I think
progress toward the goal is progress.
So, yeah, help people along the way and
then celebrate that they've made some
progress. Yeah, I think I'm just trying
to think of like the fact so I work a
lot with wellness and like eco-friendly
kind of brands. So, it's a bit easier in
that space to have immediate progress.
But I am also very conscious that
there's also different types of apps
where the end goal or where you want to
get to might be a bit bigger or you
might not be able to do it at the moment
of downloading. So, let's say you've got
an app that's helping you with doing
your tax return. You might download it
with like, hey, I really need to do
this, but I don't don't need to do it
right now. But in your mind, doing the
job is doing the tax return. like and
that's what you need to work out is like
what does progress look like for them
and you can then reshape it because like
you're saying like hey I appreciate that
having a plan as part of it but not
everyone might see or understand that so
I think it's like trying to work out
with like that initial moment cuz I
think like activation is longer than
that just that initial moment but I
think it's so important with that
initial step of like showing them like
hey you are one step closer like I think
LinkedIn also does this really well it's
like where they show you like your
profile is x% complete so it's not of
huge task of doing the whole profile,
but it's I've already filled in a bit.
You know, I'm leveling up. I'm improving
it step by step with my tax return. I
might not be able to do it yet, but
maybe I've got a clear idea and I've
completed step one cuz I know which
documents I need or I've set a reminder
like a push notification that I'm going
to do it in this moment, like put it in
my calendar. Like I think it's just
trying to figure out like if you can't
get them to do it in that moment because
a lot of people download apps on the go,
you know, they see it, they think it's
interesting, they're like, "Oh, I'll try
it out sometime." How can you still like
get them in that few minutes that you
might have while they're commuting or
doing whatever, get them to feel like
this is actually going to help me
achieve what I want to achieve. And then
the retention side of it is really
interesting because that's what you also
just mentioned. It's like you got bored.
And I think that's what we also forget.
It's like our jobs to be done and our
knowledge are they evolve over time. So,
I've been using a recipe app for a long
time um to work up recipes, but they
just got repetitive. They got similar.
It didn't feel as inspiring anymore. And
that actually led me to try out a few
other different recipe apps because I
got to a point where I didn't feel
inspired the way I did before. Or maybe
my cooking is also like evolved in like,
hey, I want to try more new things or do
different things. Like, I love to cook
anyway. So, I wanted something that was
like challenging me in a way that
doesn't anymore. And I think we're going
to use a different fitness app for once.
Sorry, ladder. Really happy to still try
it out. But Sweat is a really good
example of this because I used them just
when I was starting to get into working
out. Like I'd been running a bit before
that, but like I'd not been like very
consistent in it. And I really wanted to
see a difference in it. and they had all
these programs that each time I could go
from like beginner, intermediate,
advanced and really feel like I was
getting to a next level. And I think
like that's if we go from like
activation flowing into the retention
side, I think it's also like working out
like how is their job to be done
changing over time and what do they need
to get to next level? What is it that's
going to lose them? And that's where
your trend customers are so important to
speak to them because if they' spoken to
you and asked them like, "Hey, what's
going on?" We're like, "I'm really bored
at this thing. I just don't feel
motivated anymore. And the irony is they
probably had the content to keep you
engaged, but they weren't making it easy
or being conscious and like proactive in
like preventing that. Yeah. And I mean,
and that's actually a good example again
to bring it back to ladder is that I had
actually downloaded the app and gone
through the onboarding. I don't know six
or nine months ago. In the intervening
time is when they added that feature to
be able to customize the workouts. But I
don't think I ever got an email saying,
"Hey, you can now customize workouts and
ladder." That's a good example of the
like retention and reactivation is that
don't forget as you add things and
create new features and refine things.
There are people who have previously
used the app who may come back or may
get activated for the first time by
showing them that you now solve this
better in this new way or you now solve
this other problem that they had at the
time but you didn't solve that problem.
So yeah, it's a powerful framework for
retention as well and reactivation. We
promise this is not an ad for ladder.
Neither of us lost by ladder, but the
irony is we double one workout between
the two of us and ladder. But yeah, I
think it's definitely like a great way
to also get people back is like this is
why I think it's so important to have a
way within your app to identify jobs to
be done. So even if you're not being
direct and asking the question, knowing
specific content or knowing specific
actions or parts that people will use if
they have a specific job to be done
means that when you then speak to
churned customers of that job to be
done, you understand why they churned,
what were they missing, what never spoke
to them if they never even activated,
you can then use that to also segment
and push people hopefully back in. And
ideally, you know, like it's easier to
keep them on board initially, but if you
haven't managed to do that or you're
still evolving and how you speak to it
or you've expanded the jobs to be done
you're working with like ladder seems to
have done, then you can basically still
go back like you said and and pull
people back in and show them like, hey,
now we do get it. Like, you know, we let
you down with this. We get it. It wasn't
good enough. and it's a physical
product, but I saw a um laundry
detergent that like basically people
weren't happy with the packaging of it.
And they sponsored it was called Tallow
and Ash. It's an eco-friendly laundry
detergent in the UK. They sponsored a
post about saying, "We're sorry about
our previous packaging. It wasn't good
enough. We've got new packaging." And it
was such a weird thing to sponsor and
like do as an ad. It was just an organic
post probably on their social that
they've just boosted up boosted to get
more reach. But I actually thought it
was genius because it was basically
saying like, "Hey, sorry. We weren't
good enough for what you needed. You
know, you came to us because you wanted
to reduce waste, but then it was making
a mess and you don't want to make a mess
when you're doing your laundry." And
like just being very direct about that
like, "Hey, we're sorry we weren't
fulfilling your job to be done. We
weren't helping you in the best possible
way, but now we are and this is how
we're going to do it and make it better
for you." There's so much more we could
talk through about retention and
reactivation with jobs to be done, but I
did want to touch on monetization before
we wrap up. So, how do you think about
jobs to be done in relation to
monetization? Yeah. So, I think one of
the key parts is what we started with is
like who's actually spending the most
because you're going to have customers
with a high LTV and you're going to have
customers with a low LTV. And if we look
at like the fact that like cost of
acquisitions are going up and up and up,
the people who have that high LTV,
understanding like what jobs to be done
have a higher LTV versus those don't
should be determining who you're
focusing on. And as a result, that's
actually also helping you improve your
monetization because you're basically
focusing more on those high value
customers and serving them well versus
trying to serve the loudest voice in
there. I think that's one side of it.
Another side of it is that often I see
like brands shaping their pricing around
their the specific jobs to be done of
users and having different packages
based on like hey what are you trying to
achieve? what job to be done do you
have? Because for some jobs to be done,
like you'll see that they need all of
your features and with other ones, they
only need part of it. And they should
have that option then to basically if
those are both strong jobs to both have
a lot of potential to spend, but one
might be spending, you know, slightly
more over a shorter period of time
versus slightly less over a longer
period of time. You can also look at
like how can we shape our different like
package options to really speak to them
and make sure that like people can
figure out what's the right one for
them. If we look at like MIMO I think
people are sick of and maybe sick of our
working out or they're really inspired
to work out because of this. If we look
at MIMO the coding app there's people
who want to learn to code just for fun
and there's people who want to learn to
code because they really want to become
a developer. Now, I know from my
conversation with Catcher, their
previous like head of marketing and
growth that that first audience is more
valuable, but they do have like a
different like ti and like if I'm not
mistaken in terms of like how actively
you use it, how much support you get,
like what features do you need because
someone who's just casually playing
around with it might not want as much,
but they might still be a valuable user.
So, I think that's the other one is like
seeing like do jobs to be done have
different like requirements and
different like also like amounts that
they're willing to pay so that you're
not just blanket pricing everything but
that you're adjusting it according to
what they need and also according to
what they're comparing you to cuz I
think that's why I'm going to go back to
ladder. I'll leave it. I had another
ladder example. But yeah, I think it's
working out like what will allow you to
also charge them the right amount that
they're willing to spend on that job to
be done. And I think that's that final
also part of it is like when you become
a painkiller, so an unmissable app in
their life that they really need and
want to use constantly. People are less
price sensitive. They aren't going to
care as much when you increase things.
They aren't going to be as difficult
around it because they see you as
something irreplaceable. And so if
you've made yourself irreplaceable,
you're going to see those conversions
rates go up. you're going to see that
you're going to be able to put through
price increases so much easier because
you become such an integral part of
their lives. This is something we've
talked about on the podcast here and
there, but I I do think this idea of
being able to charge more for users who
find more value is where things are
going to go next with subscription apps.
And and again, we already see this in
the biggest apps, Tinder creating a $500
a month subscription tier. And we've
talked about it at times that if you're
early, don't complicate things with
multiple subscription tiers. Like focus
on the higher value job to be done and
just, you know, stay focused. But I do
think taring is such a powerful thing
when the time is right. Too early,
you're probably just going to like screw
up and divide your focus and complicate
the product at a time where you just
need to be moving forward and moving as
fast as you possibly can. But it is such
a powerful thing that like you said once
you're solving a really painful thing in
a really elegant way, your pricing power
is so much more than you even realize.
But then on the flip side, I think
what's happening to a lot of apps as
well is that they're charging so much
that it only makes sense for the users
who are perfectly aligned with that
value prop. And by introducing a lower
tier, you can retain users who don't
need those other features, who don't
find it as valuable. This something I'm
actually after advising not to start it
too early. I'm actually right now
considering even though, you know, my
weather app, it made 100K last year. You
know, it's like showing signs of product
market fit. It's headed the right
direction, but I've been charging $40 a
year because we have really expensive
data. But what I've realized is that the
job to be done for a lot of my users
isn't that expensive data. I can just
use the cheap Apple weather data and
create a lower price tier at $20 a year
instead of $40 a year, which is pretty
expensive for a weather app. I don't
know if I'm going to do it right away,
but I will eventually create two
separate tiers where those more advanced
like multiple data sources is in the
more expensive tier. And then the kind
of more simple just use Apple weather
data will be the lower tier. And that
will also even be a great retention plan
for those who, oh, it's it's a great
app, but I don't want to pay $40. Well,
hey, here's the $20 option. So depending
on where you're at in the stage of your
app, you should be thinking like what
are those jobs to be done that are more
valuable and is there an opportunity to
add another tier? And and when you're
solving new problems, that's a great
time to think about that as well is if
you create a really big new feature that
solves a new job to be done or solves an
existing job to be done in a much much
much better way. That's a great
opportunity to introduce that higher
price tier where you bring a lot of the
users who are already paying and
increase that revenue per user by
introducing this new feature. And it's
also a lot easier than just raising the
price across the board. It's like, hey,
we're giving you this brand new thing,
but it's going to cost more. There's so
many ways to apply jobs to be done
across the app. Monetization,
activation, messaging, ads. Yeah, it's
been so fun talking through all this and
really appreciate you coming on the
podcast to talk about all this. Yeah,
likewise. Like, and I think you're right
like it's it's not a matter of like can
it impact it. It's like thinking of the
right stage for you. And I think like
that's like if there's one like
overarching takeaway for it is like when
you're using jobs to be done like apply
it in a way that's right for you at the
current stage you're at. If you're
starting out, focus on working it out.
Working out like what is that job to be
done? What are the hesitations? What are
they using? right now, what is their
perceived value of solving this problem?
Use that to work out that initial
pricing because it's not about how much
it costs you to like sort that data. End
of the day, like if they don't see value
in it, like you said, like not every
user does. They don't care. They don't
care what your costs are. They really
don't. How much do they value this
problem being solved? How much have they
spent on it? And how can you basically
make them feel like they're resonating?
If you're at a later stage and you
already have an an existing user base
and you're already quite good at
speaking to a certain job to be done,
use it as a way to identify an
additional audience, like if you've
already really feel like you've done
everything for that initial audience,
but you're struggling to grow because
you've kind of got the most out of your
first niche, use it as a way to figure
out like, okay, what are other jobs to
be done that I'm already kind of
serving? Maybe I don't have a perfect
yet, but I could be serving it more. And
maybe that will be the inspiration for a
separate price tag. Maybe it'll be an
inspiration to add in a certain feature.
Or maybe it'll be an inspiration to
actually remove certain fluff that isn't
serving any of them that will make you
more applicable to them because you can
make sure that they get closer and
quicker to that aha moment. So I think
it's really trying to work out like
where are the issues and I always said
like there are signals if you don't
understand this. If you're asking your
team like you know what is it we do and
you know who's our target audience and
everyone's answering completely
different things. If you're struggling
to like convert them and activate them,
but you're seeing that once they get it,
once they really get it, they're
retaining, that's usually a signal that
hey, you haven't got that quite right
and you're not speaking to their jobs to
be done enough early on because you're
having to work so hard to get them to
that next point. And that's often also
the great thing then because it means
like, hey, fundamentally we got
something here, but we just need to
figure out how to bring it across. And
that's where done is nothing more than a
tool, but it's a very powerful way to
bring that across. Yeah. Well, I think
that's a fantastic place to wrap up. It
is such a great tool across the entire
life cycle from messaging to activation
to retention to monetization. Anything
you want to share as we're wrapping up?
No, I think that definitely helps you uh
move on with it. If anyone wants more
content on this, I'm regularly writing
for Revenue Cat. So, there's every month
a few new blog posts and I regularly
come back to one of my favorite topics.
And you can also check me out on
LinkedIn. Uh I share also a lot of tips
and examples there as well. Who knows,
maybe ladder will be one of my uh newest
examples after this.
Yeah, great follow on LinkedIn. If
you're not already following Daffany on
LinkedIn, she posts a lot of great
stuff. So definitely follow her there as
well. Well, thank you so much for coming
on the podcast. It was really fun
chatting through all this and I I think
there's so many great takeaways for
people to, you know, we shared a lot of
examples and and hopefully, you know,
people listening can take those examples
and reframe them into their own app of
like, you know, how do you think about
those people like me who didn't see the
right ad and how do you find those
different solutions? You know, not
everybody has a fitness app. We talked
about ladder too much on the podcast,
but hopefully people can generalize some
of those examples and think through how
this works out in their own app. It's
the most powerful way to understand it
because it brings the human aspect back
to it all. And it's when you realize,
hey, I've been in these moments myself
and I can identify with how someone's
feeling, even if it's a different type
of art. It helps you see those moments
for your own app. So, I think examples
are the way to go with this because I
think that's the issue why a lot of
people have heard the the phrase, they
know like, oh yeah, we should focus on
jobs done. should work on our messaging.
But it's a harder thing to fully get
wrap your head around. And I actually
find like the more examples I give, the
more you start to see what I like to say
life through job to be done uh glasses
because you start to think of like
what's the underlying job to be done for
everything you're doing and also other
people doing. It ruins it slightly, but
it's also very helpful because it helps
you work it out better for yourself. So
yeah, and there's loads of practical
tips and examples for your ads as well
of what you can be doing there for
improving your onboarding. Um, so
definitely take that along too and apply
it to your own setup. Awesome. Well,
thanks so much for joining me. This is
so much fun. Thank you. Appreciate it.
Thanks so much for listening. If you
have a minute, please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by
chat.subclub.com to join our private
community.
[Music]